[♪ soft music playing]
[birds chirping]
[boy panting]
[BOY] This is really bad!
I'm a goner!
[exclaims]
[monster growls]
[boy pants]
[knights grunt]
[KNIGHT 1] Hey!
[♪ tense music playing]
[KNIGHT 1] Shit!
The fuath--
O Great Zelkoff, hear me.
[boy pants]
What the heck
is she doing over here?
Come on, let's go. Come on!
[monster growls]
[monsters munching]
[KNIGHT 1]
I must catch the coffin thief!
[MAN 1] No. We'll make
a run for it. Send the signal.
[KNIGHT 1] Run? Like a coward?
But we swore to protect it.
Oh, shit!
This could be it for me!
-[boy pants]
-[monster growls]
[KNIGHT 1] It can't be!
You mean the Temple is--
[KNIGHT 1] Please, help me!
[screaming]
[boy screams]
[grunts]
[groans]
-[gasps]
-[monster growls]
[gasps in fear]
Xylo!
Help me already!
It's gonna eat me!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[grunts in effort]
[monster growls]
[boy screams]
[boy pants]
Stop moving!
You're gonna bleed out!
It hurts. Let me die!
You can have me
resurrected later!
Shut your mouth!
Like hell
I'll haul your corpse around.
[BOY] I'm begging you!
I can't even use another body!
I mean,
that's all they need to--
Listen up. It's not that simple.
Resurrecting a hero like us
means dragging their souls
straight out of hell,
and jamming it back
into their corpse.
It takes a nasty toll
on your memory
and sense of self.
Have you died so many times
you forgot the price? Well?
[breathes shakily]
[Xylo sighs]
[XYLO] In any case,
there is zero chance
the Holy Knights
would even bother
to retrieve your body.
If you're so eager to die.
[blows]
The least you can do
is wait until I'm not watching.
Get ready to pull
and brace yourself.
[boy breathes shakily]
[XYLO] You know what's coming,
so grit your teeth.
[grunts]
[screams in pain]
[sighs]
[XYLO] Well,
you royally screwed up, moron.
Dotta.
Get a handle
on those sticky fingers.
[DOTTA] Couldn't help it.
I just so happened to spot
the Holy Knights transport team.
Besides, isn't it their fault
for leaving the carriage
undefended?
It would've been far easier
not to steal from them.
I only told you to get eyes
on the faeries. That's it.
[gulps]
[DOTTA] Xylo.
I saw a lot of faeries
out there.
[XYLO] Yeah, we're up against
a massive Demon Blight
this time.
According
to Command Central's briefing,
it's around 5,000.
[stammering] Five thousand?
They can't expect us
to hold that many at bay
all by ourselves!
[XYLO] They do.
The Demon Blight
will soon corrupt
this entire forest.
We're here to help
those pathetic holy knights
retreat.
No choice.
And don't expect backup.
[gasps]
Don't get any funny ideas,
either.
Try to run away,
and they'll blow your head
clean off.
[DOTTA] It's fine.
Why should I care?
I'm a hero,
so I can just be resurrected
if things go south.
As long as there's a body,
whether it's mine
or someone else's.
[XYLO] You don't get it, do you?
Every time you lose
another chunk of who you are,
and before long,
you become little more
than a walking corpse.
I refuse.
That will not be my fate.
Heroes are tools
with no autonomy.
[satisfied sigh]
We're here
to carry out our missions.
And that's all there is to it.
Delusions won't save you.
Let's get out of here.
[Dotta groans]
[XYLO] Can't sit idly by
while they tear apart the night.
Huh?
[insects chirping]
What is this thing?
[XYLO] Wait, is that... ?
-Are you out of your mind?
-[Dotta gasps]
What kind of crap is this?
Stealing a coffin
and dragging it back here?
Good question. I can explain.
See, it looked real valuable,
and one thing led to another,
as it does...
So, anyway, I thought
it might come in handy,
that's why I brought it along.
[XYLO] Idiot!
Do you really think this junk
was worth a faerie bite?
You're kidding me. Dotta.
This thing had better be empty.
-[DOTTA] I don't know.
-[XYLO] You what?
[DOTTA]
I mean, it seemed pretty heavy,
while I was carrying it.
[XYLO] Why in the hell
would you steal a corpse?
Even for you,
that makes no sense.
[DOTTA] What can I say?
It just happened, all right?
I acted without even thinking.
Anyway, that whole place
was already swarmed by faeries.
[gasps]
Stop talking,
or I may kill you
before the faeries can.
Wait, don't be hasty.
We can leave it here
if we don't want it,
then come get it.
If the knights are angry.
-[Xylo sighs, grunts]
-[giggles]
[insects chirping]
[XYLO]
From the looks of this coffin,
it's the body of a royal, noble,
or high ranking Holy Knight.
If I'm lucky,
it'll be one of the people
I've been wanting to knock out.
[♪ angelic music playing]
[DOTTA] Well, she looks like
someone important.
[XYLO] She is.
-[XYLO] And we're in trouble.
-[DOTTA] I figured.
She's gotta be a princess.
[XYLO] If only.
She isn't even a human.
That kid is a goddess.
What do you mean?
[XYLO] What I just said!
You stole a damn goddess!
That cannot be true.
Aren't goddesses
a type of weapon
created a long time ago
to fight demon lords?
That's right.
Humanity's last ray of hope.
Or that was the idea, anyway.
I don't understand.
She looks like a little girl.
But the goddesses
I've heard about
were enormous,
whalelike creatures,
or giant hunks of iron.
[horn blaring]
Time to move.
Leave her in the coffin.
Right.
[Dotta breathes shakily]
[DOTTA] A hunting horn?
Think it's the knights?
Judging by the loud volume,
it's a scouting party
or flying column.
Their status.
You can see them, can't you?
[Dotta ponders]
[DOTTA] Looks like...
a band of fuath...
and...
people dead or dying.
[knight 1 pants]
[knight 1 grunts]
Help me!
[pants]
[grunts]
[yells fiercely]
[gasps]
[knight 2 screams]
[KNIGHT 3]
Shit! There are too many!
Hold the line, men,
no matter what happens!
[knight 4 screams]
[thud]
[XYLO] It's spreading faster
than I expected.
They would've been prepared
for faerie attacks,
but nothing like this.
I've heard enough! Let's go!
We should hide somewhere
until it's over.
[XYLO] There's still a chance
for some of them.
[DOTTA] Huh?
[XYLO] A few stubborn asses
who won't die.
It's in our best interest
to save them.
[DOTTA] Are you insane?
How is dying
in our best interest?
Remember the mission.
Help the majority
of the knights escape.
Every person we manage to save
increases
our chances of success.
-[DOTTA] Huh?
-[XYLO] We're fighting.
I'll save 'em quickly.
Before the sun sets,
we'll run down the cliff.
-[GIRL] We're fighting!
-[gasps]
[GIRL] I'll...
save them.
Wonderful!
Such lovely words.
There is no mistaking
that you are my knight.
[grunts softly]
[GIRL] A good start.
I deem your efforts passable.
It is your courage
that has made you
worthy of a goddess.
[knife clinks]
[GIRL]
Is there not a battle afoot?
And lo,
'tis a battle to save
the precious lives of others.
So be it.
From a goddess, to her knight.
Your victory
is henceforth guaranteed!
[Xylo gasps]
[GIRL] In that hour,
when all enemies lie lifeless,
your voice
shall sing my praises.
And your hand
shall lavish pats upon my head!
[Dotta gasps]
[groans]
You may pat away
to your heart's content!
No amount of praise
could properly honor the majesty
that is a goddess.
I shall even permit you
to compose
a song of veneration to me!
[XYLO] Dauntless pride
and a fierce desire
for recognition.
She's a legitimate goddess.
Huh? Are you sure?
[XYLO] Dead sure.
We're in the presence
of a goddess.
Most likely the 13th one,
who has yet to be activated.
I am the great goddess Teoritta,
the guardian who bestows
blessings upon mankind!
Teoritta.
[TEORITTA] Speak, my knight.
Put a word that what you seek.
And I shall then lend form
to your prayer with great ease,
for that
is my sole reason for being.
[grunts]
That's enough.
You know there's more.
Don't be dumb.
[Teoritta gasps]
There's nothing I hate more
than a goddess.
[horn blaring]
Dotta.
[XYLO] Hurry up,
find somewhere to hide her.
[Dotta stammers]
[XYLO] I refuse
to ask a goddess for help!
[DOTTA]
What am I supposed to do?
[♪ tense music playing]
Dotta.
Directions and distance
are on you.
Where are they
most concentrated?
[DOTTA] For the record,
I advise against this.
[XYLO] I didn't ask!
A good distraction
is the only way
to support the retreat.
Have it your way!
You always do.
-[knights grunt]
-[monsters growl]
[groans]
They're at ten o'clock!
One finger's width to nine.
That way, huh?
[TEORITTA] Fascinating.
You diminutive squire
has excellent eyesight.
The hell?
What are you doing here?
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[monster growls]
Assisting.
For I am true to my word.
My knight
shall taste sweet victory!
I don't need your assistance!
[monsters growl]
[Teoritta gasps]
-They will soon be upon us!
-Stay out of it!
If you wanna help,
leave me alone!
[Teoritta grunts]
[gasps]
[TEORITTA] What was that power?
A sacred seal of heat and light.
Now stay here and hide yourself.
[knight grunts in effort]
We'll keep them occupied.
Hurry and--
[monster growls]
[Xylo grunts]
[Dotta gasps]
Ugh.
-I think I'm gonna be sick.
-[XYLO] Dotta!
There's no time to waste.
Get in there!
Just keep firing.
Sure.
I've just gotta prepare myself.
[gasps]
Hold on! I'm not ready!
[gasps in awe]
I hit it. That was amazing!
And with just
an old thunder staff.
Missing would be more impressive
with these numbers.
Keep up the support fire,
and don't you dare hit me!
[Teoritta pants]
I am here, young squire!
Worry not, for we shall prevail!
Well,
the outlook's not promising.
Oh, you look tired.
So why don't you go ahead
and get some rest?
[grunts]
Those are the last survivors!
-[XYLO] I'll get them.
-Huh?
To hell with you!
[grunts]
[moans]
[monster growls]
Sorry, that was so close,
but it's harder to hit
when I'm far away.
Just keep it up!
I'm going to finish them off!
For real?
[hesitates] Here I come!
Take heart
in what I swore to you!
Patience, my knight.
[Teoritta grunts, pants]
[owls coo]
[insects chirping]
[metal rattles]
[XYLO] Ah, I see you survived.
[KNIGHT 1] You saved us. And
I didn't expect reinforcements.
[XYLO] Get out of here, quickly!
But what of you?
Wait! You are one
of those monstrous penal heroes.
In our own midst?
[KNIGHT 2] A capital offender?
[KNIGHT 3]
What is he doing here?
Saved by his kind...
[Dotta and Teoritta pant]
[DOTTA]
I don't like the looks of this.
[XYLO] I have my orders.
So you can retreat already.
A new horde is fast approaching.
That call is not yours!
Being saved
by a scoundrel like you
tarnishes our honor!
I'm a little confused.
Shouldn't this be the part
where these guys thank us?
That's how it goes for heroes.
Now point that sword
somewhere else.
Your intentions are clear,
my knight.
It would be most ignoble
to abandon these lost souls.
-[Xylo gasps]
-I see right through you.
-[KNIGHT 4] Hold on.
-[Xylo gasps]
Your glowing hair
and brilliant red eyes.
You look like...
What are lowlifes like you
doing with her?
We gave her
to the transport team!
[swords rattle]
[sighs]
Answer me!
[XYLO] If I do,
will you lower your swords?
[Teoritta gasps softly]
[sighs]
Hey, take it easy!
This is no time for squabbling
amongst ourselves.
Another wave is coming.
We have to move quickly!
[mic feedback]
[MAN] Xylo! Dotta!
Can you hear me?
Venetim, you need to warn us
before you do that!
[VENETIM] We're in deep trouble.
Everything's falling to pieces.
It's a complete mess!
Be more specific.
You think everything
is a complete mess.
[VENETIM]
I mean it! It's such a mess,
It could spell the end
for all of us.
Xylo, do you have a minute?
[XYLO] Hell, no!
-[monster growls]
-[thud]
[XYLO]
I'm assuming you heard that.
Still think I'm free to chat?
[VENETIM] I'll admit
it sounds like a bad time.
But if I don't tell you now,
you'll absolutely be angry
at me later.
[XYLO] Then spit it out!
[VENETIM]
The Holy Knights' main force
is currently
marching straight
for the Demon Blight.
[gasps]
[insects chirping]
[KNIGHT 1] Understood.
Report to the Temple at once.
[KNIGHT 2] Sir!
[background chatter]
[XYLO] Venetim, say that again.
[gasps]
You'll be angry at me later
if I don't tell you now, so--
-[XYLO] Not that! Next part!
-[mic feedback]
[VENETIM] Right.
It appears the Holy Knights
stationed in the forest
over there have regrouped.
They're forming ranks,
and preparing for battle
against the blight.
Those soldiers
seem to be dead set
on stopping it
from advancing any further.
The hell?
What are they thinking?
[VENETIM]
I obviously have no clue
what's gotten into them.
Hey!
What's your captain playing at
with this last stand?
You have a direct order
to retreat.
Don't tell me.
[XYLO] Was this your genius plan
from the outset?
[grunts]
[KNIGHT] That's right.
Captain Kivia gave us the order.
Kivia?
That fool sent you to die.
How dare you?
Our captain
has our unwavering trust.
We fight for the captain's honor
and for that
of the Holy Knights.
We would not hesitate
to lay down our lives
for either.
[Xylo chuckles]
Pathetic.
What do you think you'll achieve
in the state that you're in?
[VENETIM] Um, going back
to what I was talking about.
Whatever it is, say it already!
[VENETIM] Shouldn't you
just rescue them?
If over half
of the Holy Knights die,
that's a failed mission
for the Hero Unit.
You won't simply die.
You might get resurrected
and burned at the stake.
Regardless,
it will be painful
and quite unpleasant.
That sounds bad. What now, Xylo?
[TEORITTA] Why has your heart
fallen to such despair?
There can be no greater honor
than to save another soul
from certain peril.
Am I wrong, my knight?
[XYLO] Quiet, both of you!
Venetim. How far
have the dead men walking
made it?
[VENETIM]
Huh? Oh, uh, they, um--
[XYLO]
You're just now looking into it?
Of course not.
What do you take me for?
I believe they've gathered
at the second crossing point
along the Purcell River.
Do whatever you can.
The second crossing point.
[♪ tense music playing]
[XYLO] Don't even think
about joining up with them,
unless
you want to be a hindrance.
[KNIGHT] We made a choice.
Vow to fight and die
alongside Captain Kivia.
It's not something
a hero would understand.
[XYLO]
Just head south and get lost.
We drove back the faeries
that were attacking
your flying column.
You did?
[XYLO] Retreat to the south end
of the forest,
and you'll find the team
that oversees us.
Give that ass Venetim
a black eye for me.
I'll handle this.
And then
give that captain of yours
a piece of my mind.
[grunts]
You truly intend
to support our retreat
and aid our captain?
Hey, Dotta.
The mission isn't over yet.
[DOTTA] Xylo! Are you serious?
I'm afraid I am.
We'll meet up
with the Holy Knights
and prevent them
from being routed.
[Dotta groans]
My knight
is the very epitome of honor!
I vote against it.
Can we talk about this?
I know you wouldn't wanna die
for those Holy Knights, either.
Especially since you said you--
Are you done?
If the choice was mine to make,
I'd gladly
let those bastards die.
I despise people
who throw their lives away.
But I can't.
If I let them die on my watch,
they'll have cause
to look down on me,
and that's one thing
I can't allow.
Interesting logic.
[XYLO] Let's go.
If the Holy Knights
get slaughtered out there,
we'll pay a steep price.
[water splashes]
[background chatter]
[MAN 1] Get some nourishment
while you can.
[gulping]
[gasps]
Enemy sighted!
Form ranks now!
[monster growls]
Thunder staff squad, advance!
[♪ tense music playing]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[WOMAN] Prepare yourselves.
We will hold
until the last moment!
[knight pants]
Fire!
The first wave is down!
But still,
there are way too many!
They have trolls!
[roars]
Use the thunder ballistae.
We cannot allow them
to cross the river!
[metal thuds]
[KNIGHT] Fire.
[energy swishes]
[charging buzz]
[growls]
[DOTTA]
They're in the thick of it.
The Verkle Development
Corporation's assault team.
They're strong, but won't have
nearly enough ammunition
to pull this off.
Xylo. Do you recognize
any of those knights?
[XYLO] I don't,
and I've never seen
that banner before.
Then let's stay where we are.
There's still a chance
they can tough it out.
[TEORITTA]
Utter nonsense from Craven Lips.
Does not your timid heart
crave glory?
Nor wish to share
in its sweet nectar?
Doesn't matter.
They would never let us share
in their glory.
[KNIGHT] Out of ammo!
Captain,
the ballista isn't working.
We'll have to revert
to standard weaponry.
Use pikes to block
whatever's still moving!
[knight grunts]
[knights scream]
[screams, grunts]
The faeries will likely
send another unit around back
to flank them.
The demon lord
who's leading them
is thinking strategically.
And that's the smart move.
We should meet up with them
and devise a plan of att--
Are you kidding me?
Huh? He's gone.
Guess I should have known.
[Teoritta exhales]
Did you misplace
your loyal squire?
So it seems. And now,
he's proven he's nothing
but a piece of garbage
who should never be trusted.
I'll make him pay in blood.
You finally see
that I am the only one worthy
of your trust!
You require a miracle,
do you not?
I already told you.
I won't ask a goddess.
[distant explosions]
[XYLO] Shit!
Hope my flight seal
is fast enough!
[♪ tense music playing]
[clicks tongue]
[people screaming]
Take this!
Again!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[knife clinks]
[grunts]
[knights grunt]
[monsters shriek]
[KNIGHT] Draw!
Loose your arrows!
[all gasp]
[knights scream]
[monsters shriek]
[people screaming]
[Xylo grunts]
[woman grunts]
[WOMAN] What is that?
Is that everything you've got?
Because if that's the case,
this win's too damn easy!
[XYLO] Die, die, die, die!
Just die!
[grunts]
[Xylo pants]
[spits]
[horse neighs]
Who are you?
I'm guessing you're none other
than Captain Kivia.
My knight!
Why would you go
and leave me behind?
My goddess?
What are you doing out here?
We sent you off safely
to Galtuile!
[XYLO] Calm yourself.
[KIVIA] You.
Did you attack the transport?
Why ever would I?
They're unharmed.
[XYLO] None of this mess
is remotely my fault.
In any case...
[Teoritta gasps]
I haven't made a pact yet.
Speak, my knight.
What is the meaning of this?
I told you,
there's nothing I hate more
than a goddess.
[XYLO] I'm not your knight.
Find someone else to cling to.
[Teoritta sighs]
[Kivia gasps]
Explain yourself.
Who exactly are you
and what are you doing here?
While I'd love
to give you the rundown,
not now.
There's no time to waste.
[Kivia gasps]
[XYLO] The demon lord.
[♪ tense music playing]
[grunts, growls]
[birds caw]
[shrieks]
Seems it caught up to you.
Number 47.
There's no mistaking it.
Awd Goggie.
[grunts, shrieks]
[wind blows]
[♪ tense music playing]
[monster shrieks]
[growls]
[gasps]
Incoming!
Don't let that thing
break through!
[charging buzz]
Wait! Hold your fire!
[energy buzzes]
[knights yell in terror]
[XYLO] Shit!
It erected a force field.
Now it can repel all the blasts.
It's a real tricky one.
We're gonna have
to get up close to fight it.
Don't you have
any battering rams or slings?
They're still preparing them
in the First Capital.
We'll have to hope
our scorched earth seals work.
-[KIVIA] Engineers--
-[XYLO] Don't do it.
You'll destroy
everything in sight,
including the seal users
and every last one of us!
[energy buzzes]
[monsters growl]
It's suicide to mount a defense!
We should fall back
and head east.
[KIVIA]
I will not waver. We fight!
[gasps]
Don't be foolish!
Our only mission here
is to support your retreat!
Is that what you're doing?
[gasps]
Are you a hero?
I am. That a problem?
High Command in Galtuile
has granted captains like me
the right
to make the final call!
As such,
I will lay down my very life
in pursuit of honor!
I don't care
about your damn honor!
Honor is all that matters!
[groans]
[XYLO] I've heard enough.
I don't know what's driving you
to do this, but don't you care
that you're dragging us down
with you?
Why should I care
about the life of a hero?
You're scum. Too low
for even death's release.
As for her, explain at once
why you have the goddess!
He's my knight.
Xylo guides my way.
[KIVIA]
I ordered for the goddess
to be sent to Galtuile,
knowing we would die here.
To see that critical mission
through to the end!
Yet now...
[gasps]
Hold on.
You're Xylo?
[gasps]
It's here.
-[Xylo gasps]
-[monster shrieks]
[XYLO] This cannot be real.
[♪ eerie music playing]
Heads up!
[people screaming]
I need damage reports!
Xylo! There!
[monsters shriek]
[people screaming]
[KNIGHT 1]
What the hell are those things?
[KNIGHT 2] No! Stay back!
[man screaming]
[people screaming
and grunting]
It's a massacre!
[monster growls]
[people screaming]
[growling, screaming]
At any cost, hold!
[KNIGHT 1] Dammit!
We can't take much more!
-[Xylo grunts]
-[knife clinks]
[explosion]
Still two left.
You need not worry!
[monster roars]
[grunts]
[Xylo yells fiercely]
[monster growls]
-Our luck ran out.
-What are you doing?
[people screaming]
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[man screaming]
[Xylo pants and grunts]
[TEORITTA] My knight...
you must rise.
[grunts]
The time has come
for you to awaken my power.
Should you refuse,
every soul present
shall die a tragic death.
[Xylo grunts]
[XYLO] I guess we're screwed.
I would rather die
than ever trust a goddess again.
[grunts]
Kivia! Come claim your goddess!
Make the damn pact yourself!
[XYLO] Kivia! Answer me!
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[people screaming]
[panting]
[metal thuds]
[gasps]
[screaming in terror]
[grunts]
[Xylo pants]
-[TEORITTA] Xylo.
-[Xylo gasps]
[TEORITTA]
You are my chosen knight.
Unless you act,
many more precious lives
shall be lost.
Do you find that acceptable?
[XYLO] Be quiet.
I'm trying to think.
[TEORITTA] All is well.
You may despise me
if your heart insists.
And wish ill upon all goddesses.
For it matters not!
Victory shall still be yours.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[XYLO] Piece of shit!
Do it!
There's no other way
out of this.
It shall be done.
But first, such a divine pact
requires an offering.
[grunts]
[TEORITTA]
The price to be paid is--
I'm aware.
Did I guess right?
Teoritta. Help me win.
Xylo. Swear, now and forever,
to exemplify the majesty
befitting my knight.
[XYLO] I swear.
Just get on with it.
Very well.
Now, my knight.
Rejoice! I grant you
the power of a goddess.
[♪ dramatic music intensifies]
And... there I go.
[XYLO] Once again,
I'm choosing
to throw my life away.
[grunts]
[TEORITTA]
The pact has been made.
The veil of your mind
has been lifted for me.
What manner of blessing
shall you request of me?
[XYLO] That. And make it flashy.
Time to drive them back.
[TEORITTA] A valiant standoff.
Your resolve is laudable.
So be it.
By the grace of my power,
I shall gladly
offer you my blessing!
Kneel down!
Pray to the goddess of swords,
Teoritta!
[♪ adventurous music playing]
[monsters growl]
[gasps]
[indistinct chatter]
I trust that was satisfactory.
And now I give you permission
to praise my sublime power
and worship me
as much as you please!
[Xylo growls]
[TEORITTA] Do you hear?
I've granted you permission.
-Now, pat my head.
-[XYLO] Sorry.
The mission comes first.
And that means killing
every last one of them!
[monster roars]
[yells fiercely]
[monster growling]
-Keep them coming!
-[TEORITTA] With ease.
Though I expect ample praise
when the deed is done.
You'll have it
if we survive this!
Here we go!
[XYLO] Keep it up!
More, more, more!
Don't stop!
[KIVIA] What's... happening?
[Xylo scoffs]
[XYLO] Still alive?
Kivia! Once you've cleared out
the last of them,
get the wounded to safety.
You expect me
to follow your command?
A disgusting hero who--
It is your only hope
of survival!
[gasps]
[XYLO]
I don't intend to die here.
Or care to watch you
and your knights perish.
Meaning...
I will kill the demon lord.
[gasps]
[XYLO] If we make it out alive,
I'll accept any punishment
that you deem fit
and answer all your questions.
[TEORITTA] Xylo,
have you chosen at last
to fight for honor's sake?
You and those feckless knights
just won't stop going on
about that crap, will you?
Fighting for honor's sake.
That's a fool's game!
[swords clink]
[gasps]
[XYLO] My motive
is my desire to inflict
unfathomable violence.
Let's get on with it!
[♪ tense music playing]
-Don't let go.
-Presumptuous.
It is my place to worry
about you fallible humans.
[roars]
[TEORITTA] Now, my knight,
shall I bestow my blessing?
No, I'll say when!
Why delay?
Do you dare underestimate me?
Even a goddess
such as you has a limit.
When you exhaust yourself,
your flames grow brighter.
Perhaps.
[XYLO] I forbid you
to die out there.
You won't get a word of praise
for that.
[Teoritta sighs]
After all,
a goddess
should leave the strategizing
to her faithful knight!
[roaring]
[XYLO] I can do it.
I'll forge a path for us!
[monster roars]
That was most impressive.
Now, it is my turn!
Not yet!
[fighting grunts]
Xylo!
[roars]
Get ready!
We're cutting through!
[Xylo grunts]
My patience is waning!
[XYLO] I said no!
That's a demon lord?
Naturally,
I'm above feelings of fear.
Goddesses were created
to strike down demon lords.
-Allow me to demonstrate.
-Almost.
[XYLO] Just a bit longer.
[monster shrieks]
[Xylo yells fiercely]
[♪ adventurous music playing]
[groans]
[yells]
[shrieks]
[scoffs]
That's a lot of howling
over one measly leg!
[shrieks]
Come at me!
Xylo.
We shall soon be surrounded!
Allow me to help you now.
Do it! Clear a path for me!
Give it all you've got!
[TEORITTA] It shall be done.
Behold my glory!
[growls]
-Next--
-Spare your words.
Your mind is like an open book,
my knight.
Can you?
Yes!
I am a goddess, am I not?
Now pray to me, with devotion!
[XYLO] Perfect.
That is exactly
what I was praying for!
[fast blow]
To hell with you,
you damn cockroach!
[monster groans]
[Xylo grunts]
[groans]
See, my knight?
I did. Now let's--
[shrieks]
Teoritta!
[thud]
[TEORITTA] Xylo! Xylo!
Xylo!
[groans]
[TEORITTA]
You're gravely injured,
and all because
you were protecting me!
[gasps]
[monsters growl]
My knight! Do you live?
You will stay with me!
[DOTTA] Uh... Xylo?
Huh?
What are you doing
in the middle of all this?
[gasps]
[XYLO] A scorched earth seal.
[coughs]
You punk!
[Dotta grunts]
You're out stealing again!
Whoa, whoa,
it's not what you think!
I, uh. went to the camp,
and it was lying there, so...
You're lucky this time.
I'd rather thank you
than kill you.
[♪ adventurous music playing]
And... what are you doing?
Look at the dial
in the shape of the grooves.
They let you choose
how it blows.
I'm just glad
it's a model I recognize.
Great. So what's next?
Gonna give the big guy
more than he bargained for!
Let's see how well
you deal with this one!
-Did you--
-We're off!
[Dotta and Teoritta grunt]
[charging buzz]
[birds chirping]
How in the... ?
Is it over?
[TEORITTA] The faerie forces
are withdrawing.
[XYLO] That always happens
as the Demon Blight fades.
I've beaten enough demon lords
to know.
I'd say
that's gotta be the dumbest way
I ever made it happen, though.
Dotta. I'll hand it to him
and his sticky fingers
for saving the day.
I'll buy him a drink
when he wakes up.
[TEORITTA] My knight.
You were brilliant!
A fierce and fearsome combatant.
The day is ours.
A victory achieved
through the grace of the goddess
at your side.
Surely you must feel satisfied
by my abilities!
[XYLO] I guess.
[TEORITTA] Well, then.
[clears throat]
[sighs]
In that case,
is it not fitting to praise
one who has done so well?
Very well.
Good job surviving.
[TEORITTA] I was not expecting
praise of that sort.
Is survival alone truly enough?
[XYLO] It's more than enough.
Take my word.
[gasps]
And yet,
should a goddess
not be held to higher standards?
What? Don't ask me.
I don't get to decide.
I suppose you don't.
Although,
I went above and beyond
mere survival!
I met your expectations
and managed
to slay a demon lord as well!
An accomplishment
I would say
very few could achieve!
Agreed.
[Teoritta chuckles]
Do go on!
You have my leave to praise me
as much as you may desire!
Come now,
there's no need to hold back!
Look,
I am prepared for my laurels!
You may proceed as you see fit!
[laughs]
Go on, my knight!
Show me I did well!
All right. I get it.
[KIVIA] I found you, at last.
I knew it.
You truly are Xylo Forbartz.
This one on the ground
is Dotta Luzulas.
So...
you stole a goddess
in transport,
took a scorched earth seal
and slew a demon lord
outside orders.
You criminals
are the lowest of the low!
[Xylo grunts]
Guess we are.
Goddess Teoritta.
You have been deceived.
We had the Thirteenth Order
of the Holy Knights
intended to deliver you
to Galtuile Fortress.
I was certain the transport team
already set out.
[grunts]
But this hero
has stolen you from them!
Then made a pact with you
without permission!
This Xylo Forbartz,
this man is a villain!
Is he, now?
Well then, that's where destiny
has taken me.
[gasps]
[TEORITTA] He is my knight.
And no matter
what you may think,
I choose to believe in Xylo.
By his sword,
all demon lords shall be felled.
He is the knight
who I find worthy of my grace.
[KIVIA] I beg you to listen.
You say that if you do not know
the crime he has committed.
That's true.
But what crime
could sway my heart?
He killed a goddess.
[gasps]
Look upon a fallen Holy Knight!
He once made a pact
with a goddess
and cut her down
with his own hand!
[indistinct chatter]
[man clears throat]
[MAN 1]
Defendant, Xylo Forbartz,
Captain
of the Federated Kingdoms,
Fifth Order of the Holy Knights.
You were seen on the night
before the incident,
leading your unit
in a supposed path
meant to intercept
the 11th demon lord.
Just before dawn,
you entered battle
alongside
your pacted goddess Senerva.
Do you have any objection
to these statements?
They are all true.
[MAN 2] He's guilty.
[XYLO] Indeed.
I did engage in combat
with the 11th demon lord.
It was brutal.
I was expecting
reinforcements to arrive,
but they never showed up.
[MAN 1] Only answer
the questions you are asked.
Reports say the defendant
suffered catastrophic losses
to his unit,
and that he used his goddess
without leave to do so.
Do you object to this report?
I object!
I was ordered.
Everything was done
with permission.
[MAN 1] We've already examined
the records
from Galtuile Fortress.
There was no such order.
[XYLO] You're lying.
We had official orders
to go there.
The message clearly stated
that Uthob City
Defense Force Unit 71--
[MAN 1] No such unit exists
in any of our records.
You forced your men
to walk to their deaths
thinking only of selfish glory
and not of their--
[XYLO] You're wrong!
[MAN 1]
Your unit has a reputation
for its callous disregard
for authority.
I have also heard
of illegal activity
committed while dispatched.
We're on a battlefield!
A captain has to trust
his own judgement!
We're granted that authority.
[MAN 1]
An authority you only have
thanks to the Federated Kingdom.
Yet, still...
the worst of your crimes by far
is your murder
of the goddess Senerva.
Do you have any objections?
[grunts]
[chain clinks]
[XYLO] That one is true.
[MAN 2] Impossible!
[MAN 3] He killed
his own pacted goddess?
[MAN 4] He's lower than a beast!
[MAN 5] Goddess killer!
[MAN 6] He should be slain!
[MAN 7]
Death's too good for him!
[WOMAN 1] Despicable!
If there had been another way,
I would have taken it!
We couldn't locate the team
we were ordered to rescue.
The reinforcements we expected
never came.
We were left out there to die!
[MAN 1]
There were no reinforcements.
How could there be
when you made everything up?
There were no orders
for this mission.
Liar!
[chain clinks]
[XYLO] Senerva...
the goddess.
All she wanted was praise
for helping our team.
She fought
with all that she had.
Asking for nothing
but words of comfort.
[♪ sad music playing]
In the end,
she exhausted
the last of her power.
She was past her limit.
And so...
I...
[Xylo pants]
[Senerva chuckles lightly]
[Xylo whimpers]
[Xylo yells]
[chain rattles]
[XYLO] Do you know what happens
when a goddess loses her power?
She becomes weak
and defenseless.
And then,
the Demon Blight
begins to corrupt her.
[MAN 1] There is no record
of this phenomenon
ever occurring.
The Temple roundly rejects it
as a possibility.
More likely,
you carved an excess
of sacred seals into yourself
and went into a mindless rage.
[XYLO] What?
Would I still be here
if that happened?
I'm telling the truth!
[MAN 1] A goddess
being taken by the blight?
How absurd!
Just listen to me.
I could not allow a goddess
to be corrupted by the blight.
She'd wreak havoc!
How could we possibly stand
against a demon lord
wielding the unbridled power
of a goddess as their own?
And Senerva.
She understood...
the corruption
had already begun.
That's why...
I had to kill her.
[MAN 8] Lord Confessor.
The defendant
continues to blaspheme
a sacred goddess
with each word he utters.
We have ascertained
all that we could need to know.
I recommend
disallowing further speech.
[MAN 1] Perhaps you're right.
No. Hold on.
Aren't you listening?
Don't you see
what you're risking here?
You can't put blind faith
in the Temple or the military!
[groans]
You have to find them soon.
If you don't act fast,
it'll be too late, and...
[gasping]
[people screaming]
[XYLO] I see now.
From the beginning,
this was nothing but a setup.
You! All of you!
[punches]
[XYLO] I will find you,
whomever you are.
I will find you,
both for me
and my knights you doomed!
I'll find you
the one who was responsible
for Senerva's fate.
[LORD CONFESSOR] Xylo Forbartz.
I'll find you...
[LORD CONFESSOR]
...to serve as a hero.
[XYLO] And I will kill you!